<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sherlock on Bloodstiller: Ethical Hacking &amp; Active Directory Security Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/sherlock/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sherlock on Bloodstiller: Ethical Hacking &amp; Active Directory Security Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/sherlock/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Common Vulnerability Scoring System (CVSS) - Complete Guide</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/articles/understandingcvssscoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jun 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/articles/understandingcvssscoring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The Common Vulnerability Scoring System (CVSS) is an industry standard for assessing and communicating the severity of security vulnerabilities. This guide serves as both a comprehensive reference for security professionals and a practical tool for penetration testers.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-cvss&#34;&gt;What is CVSS?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;CVSS provides a standardized way to score vulnerabilities on a scale of 0.0 to 10.0, where 10.0 represents the most severe vulnerabilities. The system is maintained by the Forum of Incident Response and Security Teams (FIRST) and is widely adopted across the cybersecurity industry.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NeuroSync-D HTB Sherlock Challenge: Investigating Next.js Middleware Bypass and Redis Injection</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sherlocks/neurosync-d-sherlock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sherlocks/neurosync-d-sherlock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;neurosync-d-hack-the-box-sherlock-challenge-writeup&#34;&gt;NeuroSync-D Hack The Box Sherlock Challenge Writeup:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://app.hackthebox.com/sherlocks/NeuroSync-D&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noreferrer nofollow&#34;&gt;https://app.hackthebox.com/sherlocks/NeuroSync-D&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;challenge-information&#34;&gt;Challenge Information:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficulty&lt;/strong&gt;: Easy&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Category&lt;/strong&gt;: DFIR&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario&lt;/strong&gt;: NeuroSync™ is a leading suite of products focusing on developing cutting edge medical BCI devices, designed by the Korosaki Coorporaton. Recently, an APT group targeted them and was able to infiltrate their infrastructure and is now moving laterally to compromise more systems. It appears that they have even managed to hijack a large number of online devices by exploiting an N-day vulnerability. Your task is to find out how they were able to compromise the infrastructure and understand how to secure it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;side-quest-what-s-an-n-day&#34;&gt;Side Quest: What&amp;rsquo;s an N-Day?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;An N-day is a vulnerability that is already publicly known however a patch may not be available or the user has not been able to patch the flaw just yet. This is common as rolling out updates to large organizations and networks can be a slow process.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SmartyPants HTB Sherlock Challenge: Analyzing Windows RDP Compromise Through Event Logs and SmartScreen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sherlocks/smartypants-sherlock/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sherlocks/smartypants-sherlock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;smartypants-hack-the-box-sherlock-challenge-writeup&#34;&gt;SmartyPants Hack The Box Sherlock Challenge Writeup:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://app.hackthebox.com/sherlocks/SmartyPants&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noreferrer nofollow&#34;&gt;https://app.hackthebox.com/sherlocks/SmartyPants&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;challenge-information&#34;&gt;Challenge Information:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficulty&lt;/strong&gt;: Very Easy&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Category&lt;/strong&gt;: DFIR&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Scenario&lt;/strong&gt;: Forela&amp;rsquo;s CTO, Dutch, stores important files on a separate Windows system because the domain environment at Forela is frequently breached due to its exposure across various industries. On 24 January 2025, our worst fears were realised when an intruder accessed the fileserver, installed utilities to aid their actions, stole critical files, and then deleted them, rendering them unrecoverable. The team was immediately informed of the extortion attempt by the intruders, who are now demanding money. While our legal team addresses the situation, we must quickly perform triage to assess the incident&amp;rsquo;s extent. Note from the manager: We enabled SmartScreen Debug Logs across all our machines for enhanced visibility a few days ago, following a security research recommendation. These logs can provide quick insights, so ensure they are utilised.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Files Provided&lt;/strong&gt;:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;358 Windows Event Logs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;+Important Note+: Only after completing this Sherlock purely with Event Viewer did I discover some very useful tools, &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericzimmerman.github.io/#!index.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noreferrer nofollow&#34;&gt;EvtxECmd&lt;/a&gt;&#xA; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://ericzimmerman.github.io/#!index.md&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noreferrer nofollow&#34;&gt;Timeline Explorer&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;, which would have made this easier. I would suggest using these tools, you can see how to set them in the end section &lt;a href=&#34;#side-quest-using-evtxecmd-dot-exe-and-timeline-explorer-to-easily-view-logs&#34; &gt;Side Quest: Using EvtxECmd.exe &amp;amp; Timeline Explorer To Easily View Logs:&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brutus HTB Sherlock Challenge: Analyzing SSH Brute Force Attack Through Linux Logs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/sherlocks/brutus-sherlock/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/sherlocks/brutus-sherlock/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;brutus-hack-the-box-sherlock-challenge-writeup&#34;&gt;Brutus Hack The Box Sherlock Challenge Writeup:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://app.hackthebox.com/sherlocks/Brutus&#34;  target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noreferrer nofollow&#34;&gt;https://app.hackthebox.com/sherlocks/Brutus&lt;/a&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;challenge-information&#34;&gt;Challenge Information:&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Difficulty&lt;/strong&gt;: Very-Easy&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Description&lt;/strong&gt;:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In this very easy Sherlock, you will familiarize yourself with Unix &lt;code&gt;auth.log&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;wtmp&lt;/code&gt; logs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We&amp;rsquo;ll explore a scenario where a Confluence server was brute-forced via its SSH service.&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After gaining access to the server, the attacker performed additional activities, which we can track using &lt;code&gt;auth.log&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Although &lt;code&gt;auth.log&lt;/code&gt; is primarily used for brute-force analysis, we will delve into the full potential of this artifact in our investigation, including aspects of privilege escalation, persistence, and even some visibility into command execution.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;challenge-files&#34;&gt;Challenge Files:&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Files Provided&lt;/strong&gt;:&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;auth.log&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;wtmp&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In this writeup, we&amp;rsquo;ll investigate a security incident on a Confluence server that was compromised through its SSH service. We&amp;rsquo;ll analyze two critical log files - &lt;code&gt;auth.log&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code&gt;wtmp&lt;/code&gt; - to reconstruct the attack timeline and understand the attacker&amp;rsquo;s actions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
