<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools on Hack Me Daddy</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tools on Hack Me Daddy</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>BloodServer: A Secure File Transfer Tool for Penetration Testers</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/bloodserver/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/bloodserver/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;bloodserver-a-secure-file-transfer-tool-for-penetration-testers&#34;&gt;BloodServer: A Secure File Transfer Tool for Penetration Testers&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As a penetration tester, securely transferring files during engagements is crucial. That&amp;rsquo;s why I developed BloodServer, a lightweight Python-based server designed specifically for pentesters who need a quick and secure way to transfer files in controlled environments.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Feel free to contribute to the project or report issues on my &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bloodstiller/bloodserver&#34;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;key-features&#34;&gt;Key Features&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Easy Setup&lt;/strong&gt;: BloodServer can be quickly deployed with minimal configuration.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Authentication&lt;/strong&gt;: Basic authentication is built-in to prevent unauthorized access.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;HTTPS Support&lt;/strong&gt;: Optional HTTPS encryption for secure data transfer.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;File Upload Capability&lt;/strong&gt;: Allows for easy file uploads via POST requests.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Configurable Options&lt;/strong&gt;: Customize port, username, and password via command-line arguments.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Graceful Shutdown&lt;/strong&gt;: Stop the server cleanly with a simple keyboard command.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Logging&lt;/strong&gt;: Server activities are logged for monitoring and debugging.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ol&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;requirements-and-installation&#34;&gt;Requirements and Installation&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;BloodServer is lightweight and requires only Python 3.6+ and OpenSSL (for HTTPS support). Installation is as simple as cloning the repository:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LDAPire: LDAP Enumeration Tool</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/tools/ldapire/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/tools/ldapire/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introducing-ldapire-a-tool-for-active-directory-reconnaissance&#34;&gt;Introducing LDAPire: A Tool for Active Directory Reconnaissance&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As penetration testers and security professionals, we often find ourselves needing to quickly assess and enumerate Active Directory environments. Today, I&amp;rsquo;m excited to share a tool I&amp;rsquo;ve developed that streamlines this process: LDAPire - the LDAP Checker and Enumerator.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;You can find the full source code and installation instructions for LDAPire on my GitHub repository: &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/bloodstiller/ldapire&#34;&gt;LDAPire on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s very much in it&amp;rsquo;s infancy, however I plan on adding more features.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;what-is-ldapire&#34;&gt;What is LDAPire?&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;LDAPire is a Python-based tool designed to connect to LDAP servers (primarily Active Directory Domain Controllers), perform authentication, and enumerate users and groups. It&amp;rsquo;s built with flexibility and ease of use in mind, making it an invaluable addition to any pentester&amp;rsquo;s toolkit.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
